# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hi everyone, I am Wang Gang
# 我们这里东西已经摆好了 像这些盆盆罐罐也买到了
Look we’ve got all utensils and cookware ready here
# 反正不知道为什么看到不锈钢的心情就无比的舒畅
Anyway, I don’t know why I feel so good when I see stainless steel
# 比如说像这后面 这一截全是不锈钢的 而且都是新的
Like those things behind me, they are all made of stainless steel and are all brand new
# 但是有一个灶是旧的
But one of the stoves is old
# 这个灶的话因为放的时间比较长
That stove has been idle for a long time
# 又有比较多的锈
and is covered in rust
# 然后我今天买了这个 买了一点烧碱
So today I bought some caustic soda
# 烧碱来把它洗一下
to remove the rust from it
# 还有这个工作台也是旧的 上面还有一些锈
This old workbench also has rust on it
# 也给它除一下锈 搞搞卫生
Let’s get it cleaned
# 然后搞好卫生了之后就开始买餐具啊
When I’m done with the cleaning, I’ll go shopping for more utensils and tableware
# 买那些东西就可以开火了
Then I can start cooking in here once I get everything I need.
# 现在我去找了一副眼镜 这个墨镜跟别人借的
I borrowed a pair of sunglasses from someone
# 就是等一下烧烧碱的时候戴一下
to wear when we prepare the caustic soda
# 然后再戴一副这个胶手套
Also I need to wear a pair of rubber gloves for protection
# 我们不建议在家庭里面烧这个烧碱来洗东西
We don’t recommend using caustic soda at home for kitchen cleaning
# 这个特别危险
This is really DANGEROUS
# 非专业人士切勿模仿
For non-professionals please do not imitate
# 先把墨镜带上
Let’s put on the sunglasses first
# 我以前烧碱都弄到过眼睛一次 差点瞎了
I’ve got caustic soda in my eye once before and I almost went blind
# 因为那个时候太小 不懂事
because I was too young too naive
# 好了 我们这个水已经烧开了
Okay, the water is boiling now
# 现在放烧碱进去
Now put the caustic soda in
# 放烧碱的时候一定要慢慢 慢慢的放
Make sure you add it slowly and gently
# 一次性放多了它水会满出来
If you add too much of it at once, the water will spill
# 所以干这个活不建议普通人在家里面做 特别危险
That’s why we don’t recommend people to do this kind of work at home. It’s very DANGEROUS.
# 这个烧碱一下子放进去就化了
The caustic soda melts immediately
# 现在已经变成了超强碱水
It’s now a super-alkaline solution
# 给它一点一点的淋在这个上面
Pour it on the top little by little
# 一次不要淋太多
Not too much at a time
# 这个不能接触皮肤 接触皮肤会腐蚀皮肤而且会特别痒
It can erode your skin and make you feel itchy so you should avoid contacting it with skin
# 如果弄破了的话皮肤会烂
It may also rot your skin
# 所以一定要小心泼这个
So please be careful when you pour it.
# 大家可以看一下这个锈 一下子就掉完了
As you can see, the rust can be easily scrapped off.
# 除锈特别好
It does an excellent job on removing rust
# 这个只适合我们厨房里面这样子做 不适合家庭的
But this method is only suitable for our kitchen, not for household use
# 家庭操作起来特别危险
It’s extremely DANGEROUS to operate at home
# 也不建议这样子去干
I wouldn’t recommend you do this
# 而且这个除油特别厉害
This is also an excellent grease remover
# 除锈除油都可以
It works well on removing both rust and grease
# 也有的人专门做这个的 他是用那个高温手枪给它冲
Professional kitchen cleaning normally uses a high-pressure washer
# 里面就是烧碱
with caustic soda solution
# 这个千万不要触碰到皮肤
Don’t let it touch your skin
# 好啦 我们把这一锅水端到那边去洗那个锅 这一锅碱水
Okay, let’s bring this pot of alkaline solution over there to clean that wok range
# 在下面不好洗
It’s not easy to clean here
# 我站上去吧
I’ll stand up there
# 好啦 现在我们冲水啦
All right, let’s flush it with water
# 这个油渍呀是很容易去掉的你看
Look how easy removing this grease is!
# 这冲一下特别干净
It becomes very clean after a quick rinse
# 冲一下这个上面
Let’s rinse the top part a bit
# 好了 我们今天就简简单单弄一下
Okay, let’s make this simple today
# 一般我们在厨房里面是每天都要用洗洁精这样子搞一下卫生
Usually we use detergent to clean the kitchen everyday
# 然后一个星期要用烧碱来烧
We also use caustic soda every week
# 然后这个不锈钢上面全部都要用烧碱来给它去一下油渍
to remove the grease on the stainless steel
# 我们这个如果说长时间不弄的话
If we get lazy for a long time,
# 一旦这个油多了就很难洗
the grease will accumulate and become hard to wash
# 如果我们一个星期做一次大扫除的话
If we do deep cleaning every week,
# 基本上就不会有什么油 特别干净
we can keep our kitchen clean and tidy
# 就想说工作的时候特别的心情比较舒畅一点
And it makes me feel much better when I’m cooking
# 如果摸到哪儿都是油哪儿都粘手的话可能就很不爽
I hate the feeling of grease being everywhere and sticking to my hands
# 好了 本期视频就到这里了 拜拜
Okay, that’s it for today’s episode. Bye!
# 然后每天搞一点 再搞几次就可以了
We’ll continue tidying for a few more days and then the place should be ready